Today's video is credited to Mr.
Deepak's comment. Deepak ji,
thank you for your comment. If you all
want to understand the details of Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Company Limited's Nishit Ayush Plan, then check the description of today's video.
You will
find the link to the Nishit Ayush Plan video.
You all know that every video on the channel comes according to
your questions, suggestions and comments.
So stay connected with us.
Like and share the video. Don't forget to
subscribe to the channel and turn on the all notification
bells. And do
tell us in the comment section
which plan you want the next video to be about. Hello
everyone, a very warm welcome to all of you. You are
watching You The Real. I am your own
personal advisor Amitraj Sharma. So first of all,
we will understand the eligibility criteria of Aditya Birla Sun Life's Vision Life
Income Plan.
If you are up to 60 years of age, then
you are eligible for this plan because the
entry age limit is from 30 days
to 60 years. That is, even if your child is
more than 30 days old, you will still be
able to avail this plan.  What you have to do to know the age based
eligibility criteria policy term for the child is to
subtract your age from 100.
If you take a plan for a minor, then the
premium payment term should be till they turn 18 years old.
And if you
take a plan for yourself or say till
what is the maximum age we can pay the premium, then
you can pay the premium till the age of 75 years
or even less than that is okay
because the minimum sum assured limit is
₹1 lakh and the premium payment
term options are 8 years, 10 years, 12
years, then from 15 years to 40 years okay.
If the premium payment is for 8 years, 10 years and
12 years only, then the annual premium
limit is at least ₹2500000. If you are from 15 years to
40 years, then the
premium should be ₹33880 annually.
You get all the modes of premium. Okay, let
us understand Aditya Birla Sal Life
Insurance
Which category of plan is the Vision Life Income Plan of Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Company Limited? It is a
non-linked participating whole life
insurance plan. In simple words,
non-linked means that the
premium we are paying to the
insurance company is
not investing it directly in equity or stocks. It is
participating, that is, at the
end of the financial year, the company will announce a bonus.
If it announces it, then it will be paid in a guaranteed manner. Along with
this,
as soon as you complete the premium payment term in the plan,
you start getting regular income. If it is a whole
life insurance
plan, then your
life remains insured during the policy term. If something happens to you, then the
benefit is paid to the nominee. Let
us now understand how the benefits of the Vision Life Income Plan of
Aditya Birla Sun Life Insurance Company
Limited
work in the policy. The
first benefit you get here is the
survival benefit, which is of two types. The
first is guaranteed and the second is non-guaranteed. The
guaranteed one is 5% of your base sum assured,
which is non-guaranteed.  We call it
bonus. Right bonus is available in two ways. First, the
bonus will keep accumulating during the premium payment term
and as soon as
your last year of premium payment term is completed,
you will get that bonus. After that,
you will get it in the form of regular income, that is,
after the completion of the premium payment term,
you will get a guaranteed income of 5% of your basic sum assured.
Along with that, you
can also get a cash bonus if the company announces it. Yes, when it comes to
maturity
benefit,
you can get a terminal bonus along with sum assured and maturity.
You know that
only the insurance company can tell you the exact amount.
To know the sum assured and maturity, you have to
compare your base sum assured,
which is your base premium. You withdraw 105% of whatever you have
paid in the plan.
Whichever is higher of the two is the
sum assured and
maturity. To understand these two benefits, let
us take the example of Aditya Build Sun Life Vision Life
Income Plan. That too, the
policy  Of the brochure itself so that if you
read the policy brochure, you can understand. Let's
assume Mr. A is
35 years old and is taking a premium payment term of 15 years. If
you subtract 35 from 100, then
he gets a
policy term of 65 years. Right, the
base sum assured that he is taking here is 124000. So, the
annual base premium being paid for it is
₹146000. So
what will be the guaranteed income? When does 5% of the base sum assured start getting?
Regular income is received only after the premium payment term is completed, that is,
15 years of premium payment term, that is, you will have to wait for
15 years. Right,
what will happen during the 15-year premium payment term? So, the
bonus rate is ₹440 on a sum assured of ₹1,
or let's say it is 4% of the base sum assured
or ₹146000.  Here we will
calculate 4% of ₹1,44,000 and multiply it by 15 to get the
premium payment term for 15 years. Then the bonus will be accumulated to
₹46,400. Now, as soon as the
premium payment term for 15 years is completed, it will be the
last year. At that time, the award bonus as per
the policy brochure will be paid to the policy holder
here, ₹46,400. Okay,
and as soon as one and a quarter years are completed, the
guaranteed income period will start from there, that is, if
you subtract the premium payment term of 15 years from 65 years, then the
guaranteed income period of 50 years will come out
and the guaranteed income per year will be ₹62,000.
Because if you calculate 5% of ₹1,24,000, then it will be ₹
62,200 only. Right, now
here we are assuming that the
rate of cash bonus remains 4% throughout the policy
term.  Here we are
assuming that according to the rate of cash bonus, the
cash bonus will be
Rs. 9760. So, in the 50 year
guaranteed income period,
we are assuming that the yearly income
benefit will be Rs. 9760, which is guaranteed at Rs. 62200. That means,
they will keep getting the yearly income benefit of Rs. 960. So, if
we calculate the total sum of income
benefit here, then if we multiply 11960 by 50, then
this
amount becomes around Rs. 5598. If the bonus rate remains the same, then it is
fine. Now suppose maturity
comes, then the sum assured on maturity is
maturity plus terminal bonus. Now,
what do we do to calculate the sum assured on maturity?
Yes, we compare our base sum assured, which
we have taken as Rs. 124000, with the
total paid premium, which is ours
here, Rs. 1  The annual
premium that we are assuming will be Rs. 690. Right, if we
take out 105% of it, then the
amount will be Rs. 15757 24.50.
This will be our sum assured on maturity, that is,
Mr. A can get
Rs. 15757 2450 as maturity benefit plus terminal bonus, if any. So,
you can calculate both these benefits in this way.
Now we will learn about the death benefit here. Let us
assume that Mr. A
dies after completion of 10 years of the policy, that is,
within the premium payment term. In 10 years, if we
assume the bonus rate to be Rs. 4%, then the bonus for 10 years will be Rs.
976. Right, if we
assume the same bonus rate, then what do we have to calculate here? We will have to
calculate the sum assured on death. Because
we are talking about death benefit, so if
we multiply the annual premium by 10, then it will become Rs.
460.  Yes, then the
premium we pay in 10 years will be
10460 at the rate of annual premium, if we
take out 105% of it then it will become
10483, then if we compare it
with the basic sum assured then 124000 will be the
highest here, that will be the sum
assured on that right, now in some conditions the
amount may be more or less, sometimes it may happen
that the total premium paid may be more, okay, for
this reason I have explained it clearly, so
here the policy brochure tells us
that if the life assured dies during the premium payment term, then in such a case the
company pays the sum assured on death along with the
award bonus accumulated till the date of
death along with the terminal bonus,
okay, so what does our death benefit
say here, 124000, our sum assured on that right,
cured bonus of 9600 and terminal bonus
right, if it happens then the death benefit would be
1741600  Plus terminal bonus B, then the
company will pay it. So in this way, if
death occurs during the premium payment term, then the
death benefit will be calculated.
Now, if the matter arises that
death occurs after the premium payment term, then let us take a logical
scenario. Let us assume that
Mr. A dies after completion of 30 years of the policy. In
such a situation,
sum asshot on the bonus from the last policy
year, that is, according to the bonus rate announced in the last year,
1 year
bonus right and terminal bonus, then within 15 years,
our total paid premium will be ₹
15690 at the rate of ₹1.46. Now we will calculate 105% of it, that is,
105% of the total paid premium, so it will
amount to 15757.2450 paise. And
if we assume the bonus rate to be 4% here, then
our base sum of ₹1.44000 is ₹1.44000, we will
calculate 4% of it here. Okay, so
our bonus will come here.  It will be Rs.
9760. Now see, if you
calculate 10 times the annual premium or compare the base sum due with
105% of the total paid premium, then
you will come to know here
yourself because you have watched the video patiently.
Listen and see that the sum due on
death here, when we are assuming death after 30 years, will be
105% more than the total paid premium, that is, the
sum due on death will be Rs.
15757 24.50 paise, that is, if we
add the bonus amount of Rs. 9760 to Rs. 15757 24.50 paise, then Rs. 1
2484 50 paise plus terminal bonus, if any, will be
paid to the nominee. The policy will be closed. So, in
this way, you
will calculate the death benefit. If
death occurs after the premium payment term, then it is right because
otherwise you are already taking cash bonus, otherwise nothing will be left,
that is why this happens.
Now talk about it.  The question arises that from where did we take the cash bonus,
so you can see on the top of the screen that the
bonus declaration is written clearly that on the
sum amount of ₹1, how much was it on March 2022 and
how much was it on 23rd, we have been told on both sides,
now our premium payment term is
less than 19 years because we have taken it for 15 years, so on the
sum amount of ₹1,
we are getting a bonus of 040 on both the years, that is
4% of the basic sum amount, okay, now
how will you cross check this thing yourself, let me also
tell you, when you go to the website,
you will see the home option, there you will see the
option of forms and downloads, inside that
you will see the category, if
you are not able to search the bonus rate yourself, then do
not take the plan without it and
definitely take the PDF from the Telegram channel, thank you,
thank you very much to all of you